## **Aitana Hierro**

aitanahierro@gmail.com, (458) 265-1445, linkedin.com/in/aitanahierrog

#### PRODUCT MANAGEMENT & DATA ANALYTICS

Currently pursuing technical Business Analytics Masters at SCU, with 5+ years of diverse business experience including entrepreneurship. Experience includes leadership of teams of 15+ using data-driven and agile methods. Known for converting ideas into successful, market-ready products and specialized in designing data analytics models for informed decision-making.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Plug and Play Tech Center Product / Partner Success Associate

Sunnyvale, CA Apr 2022 to Sep 2023

- Led the development of a Data Analytics product to measure customer insights, leading to 80% customer retention rate.
- Managed \$600K+ in energy and sustainability corporate accounts, drove revenue growth and long-term partnerships with 12+ corporate clients such as OPPO, Ecopetrol, Mitsui & Co., Furukawa Electric, etc.

## NEXT JOB SL CEO & Co-founder

Madrid, Spain Sep 2018 to Mar 2022

- Conceptualized and built an employment platform for young professionals' first job, generating €130K+ revenue through a successful HR product launch.
- Orchestrated 25+ corporate partnerships with industry leaders: Morningstar, Telefónica, Indra, Mondelez, Orange, Adecco, Ocean Winds, Sacyr, Nestlé, Kraft Heinz, etc.
- Collaborated on 5 innovation consulting projects with clients.

## Class Spain SL Product Marketing Associate

Alicante, Spain Jun 2018 to Mar 2020

Implemented targeted marketing strategies, resulting in a 10% expansion of market share in the Alicante region.

# Juguetes Industriales S.A. (JUINSA) Product Sales Associate

Alicante, Spain Sep 2016 to Sep 2018

 Demonstrated a strong ability to understand customer needs and preferences and closed sales deals, leading to a 5% increase in sales volume.

## **EDUCATION**

## Santa Clara University, Leavey School of Business Master of Science in Business Analytics (MSBA)

Santa Clara, CA Dec 2024

• Courses: Database Management with SQL, Data Analytics with Python, Marketing Analytics, Machine Learning, Web Programming and Econometrics with R and Mathematics with R.

# Mondragon University (Teamlabs) Bachelor Degree in Leadership, Entrepreneurship and Innovation

Madrid, Spain Nov 2022

Awarded Best Leader of 2019-20 for entrepreneurship performance (out of 380 students).

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Programming Languages: Python, R, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript and PHP.

**Skills:** Product Management, New Product Development, Outbound Product Management, Product Innovation, Data Analytics, Coaching & Mentoring, Customer Relationship Management (CRM), Project Management.

## **ADDITIONAL INFORMATION**

Bi-lingual: English and Spanish.

**Volunteer experience:** as an English teacher for people in risk of social exclusion for 2 years with Caritas.

Coaching experience: mentorship of beginner entrepreneurs from the MTA Academy network.